Yo, my dog.
>> What's up, brother?
>> Who's interviewing who here?
>> All right. First time we crossed paths
was high school.
>> Yep.
>> And CJ was
250 pounds
>> back then. Maybe about 260.
>> 260.
>> And playing running back. And I do
remember being like, how are we going to
tackle this guy? This is going to be
interesting. I'm playing safety and I'm
probably 170 soaking wet and like I'm
not I had nothing to do with this guy
thankfully. I think uh I don't think you
broke any like too long on us when I was
playing so I didn't have to tackle you
but
>> No, I was an underassman so um you know
we didn't we didn't like I didn't get
the ball that much my maybe sophomore
freshman year. Um, so we didn't have to
cross paths, but um,
if I remember correctly, we won every
single one of those games, right?
>> No,
not when I was playing.
>> We we weren't that good, uh, to say the
least, uh, back then anyways.
>> But then you got us when I left, right?
>> Oh, absolutely. Absolutely. 80 yards 80
yard touchdown to to to finish the game.
I'll never I never forget it. I never
forget it. And then, um, yeah, I mean,
college, too. I mean, uh, I think I was
a red shirt freshman when you were a
senior and, uh, I remember you guys
coming coming to Auggie and this little
receiver went for like 160 on us and,
uh, had I don't know, maybe had a couple
touchdowns, but, uh,
>> yeah, man, you did your thing.
>> Always love playing in August.
>> Good times. And I think we played y'all
at home, too, maybe. And and uh, yeah,
it was always like a good little
rivalry. M
>> uh I I personally have never beaten
Mano. You know, we we came close my
maybe my junior senior year. You guys
have always come and be, you know, top
five in the country and we give you guys
your best game until playoffs. Um but we
never never got over that hump.
Nowadays, uh you know, Auggie Augi kind
of wins that match up more times than
not in the last maybe like five years or
so. But back when we played, I mean, I
I'll give it to you.
>> Unfortunately, I've had to wear the
Augie gear a couple times in the locker
room. Absolutely. But this year, Mano
gear,
>> I think we I think we got the Dove this
year, which was nice.
>> But I I don't think you gave me any gear
to wear, so we kind of just pushed it
push it aside. I I wasn't going to
remind you.
>> Let's play basketball together.
>> You can wear the Mano gear.
>> Absolutely. I got you.
>> In the locker room, guys are always
talking about their college teams,
right? Like, oh, we we we we got them
this week or um you know, I'm I'm I'mma
bring that gear for you. and me and you
playing NSIC ball, D2 ball, there's
nobody who we can talk to in a locker
room about about football games.
>> You guys kind of just shut down when
it's college football cuz you're like,
"Yeah, nothing to say."
>> Exactly. You know, when when when
everybody starts arguing back and forth
to who's better or, you know, if you
guys would have played us this year and
like I don't got anybody to talk to. So,
I all I had was you. Um so, you know, I
would circle that circle that Mano game
and that was kind of the only time that
that I'd talk about college football uh
throughout the whole year.
>> Yeah. I remember I remember when you
first came. I might have been even
during rookie camp when we met
>> and you were in the locker room and and
at that point you were just there for
the try out. Yep.
>> And um you I remember you coming up to
me and saying that you played at
Augustana and I think there's just like
a sense of pride when you think of NSIC
think about division 2 even right like
guys come in the locker room and you
kind of instantly gravitate to those
guys because you're like man I was once
in your shoes and so there's like sense
of pride you know obviously there's the
the rivalry that we have of of you know
who wins that game because they play
each other every year but there is also
just a sense of pride of like hey we
came from the same place
>> and then obviously ours goes to high
school too. Like same same level of high
school, you know, played against each
other. Like there's just like a pride of
like, hey, we've been in those same
shoes. I've been in those same shoes
that you've been in. And uh which is
cool.
>> And it's always just nice to know like
somebody else has walked the path before
you and with you. Um you know, just
knowing the knowing the battles that
you've had to go through um they're not
getting recruited like just having that
similar story. Uh like you said, I think
you just gravitate towards that. you
don't play D2 ball to make it to the
NFL. It kind of it kind of just uh it
kind of just happens and you're like,
"Oh, yeah. I guess I'll give it a shot."
Um, you know, so I guess I would say
that the the NFL wasn't like on my
radar. There was so much going going
throughout my college career. I don't
know if you can say the same thing or
not, but it was maybe those last two
years where I maybe thought there might
be a sniff of something. Um, and uh so
so then so then I'm like, "All right,
I'll give it a shot. I don't know what's
going to happen." I didn't, it's not
like I had agents pounding on my door
and scouts calling know, you know, tons
of scouts calling my coaches and I'm
like, you know, I'm going to give it a
shot. And whatever happens happens. At
least I know I can say I I I put put my
best foot forward. And um, you know,
when I got the opportunity and I saw
what you were doing, you know, right
away I ca I came to you and like asked
you like what what can I do? Uh, you
know, what what what are some of the
things that I that that I can look for
or how do I make this team? And just
looking at how you did things. um just
helped me tremendously and you know you
know knowing you came from the NSIC
knowing you did the whole regional
combine thing that I signed up for I
ended up doing a proday instead but just
just knowing you took all the same type
of paths and I'm like all right I'm I'm
I'm going to watch this guy you know
once I made once I made the team off the
trial like this this is the guy you were
the guy that I was going to look look
look look after um you know look to for
for inspiration and I remember
specifically asking you I think it was
during a preseason game I'm like Adam do
you you still get nervous for games and
uh you you looked at me and said, "No,
not really." It's like, if I'm prepared,
why do I need to be nervous? And like
that is something that I have taken with
me, you know, from year one all the way,
you know, through year 10 was like, man,
I as long as if I make sure I'm prepared
the right way, like I don't need to be
nervous. I don't need to have any
anxiousness. I can just go out there and
have fun and play and play ball. Um, so
just making sure how I did the work
during the week uh was was important,
you know.
>> Yeah. I mean, I say this a lot, but I I
feel more nervous now looking back at
that opportunity than I was in the
moment. I feel like I had kind of like a
delusional mindset of like I was just
going to play football and I didn't
really worry about not making it or
making it. Um, and so again, like I look
back at it, I'm like, man, I'm I'm more
nervous for myself right now thinking
about it than I was in the moment, which
is probably a good thing. But it was
just an opportunity to go play football
and to hopefully, again, like you said
earlier, you said that you just wanted
to know that you gave it everything you
had and if you didn't make it at that
point, you knew, hey, it's all good.
Like, I can move on. Um, and that was
kind of my mindset going into the whole
thing, right? Was I'm gonna I'm gonna do
everything I can to make it. And that
way I know if I don't that I gave it
everything I had. I have no regrets. And
so going into that that mini camp, I was
just playing football. And I remember
just maybe being a little nervous going
into it, you know, just kind of not
knowing what to expect, but then like
you get out there and it's like this is
no different than a mano practice. Like
I'm running the same routes I ran in
college that I ran in high school. just
cuz it's the NFL doesn't mean you're
doing anything like out of this world
that you've never done before. And so
other than maybe playing special teams,
I remember lining up at Gunner and being
like, I've never done this before. Uh
never played special teams in high
school or college. So, um that was a
little different, but but yeah, other
other than that, it's just football.
>> I think to to piggy back off of what he
said, too, is like I I literally had no
idea. I I had no idea what I was getting
into. I mean, the Vikings were the only
team that gave me an invite and it's
like I had no idea what an invite was. I
just know I was going to camp with all
the other drafted and undrafted guys and
whatever happens happens, you know, and
uh and like you said, once you get
there, like I'm thinking like I'm
playing with all these guys from the Big
10, the SEC, like I I just played little
division two ball. Like there's no way
like how am I going to stack up against
these guys? And you quickly realize like
no, it's just football. Like we've all
been doing this for a long time. We're
all here for a reason. Um, and I think
that right there gives you the
confidence. You're like, "Oh, I I can
play." You know, this, you know, none of
these, you know, a lot of these guys are
bigger than the guys I played with, but
you know, I'm fitting in just fine. You
know, and one other thing that came came
to my mind, I think I think I might have
asked you this when when uh when I was
at the rookie mini camp, too, when I saw
you just for a brief second, and I think
I remember you telling me that don't let
don't let you not know not knowing what
to do be a reason why you're not on the
field. And uh you know that was
something I've taken with me throughout
my whole career too. And I've said it
plenty of times to kids and whatnot. But
I I remember specifically you know it
was going to be three days of rookie
mini camp them throwing the playbook at
you. Um you know back then I played
running back but they also say hey I
want you to learn a little a little bit
of the fullback stuff too. Um so
learning two different positions in
those three days. Um making sure I knew
where to be how to do things. And I
think that was a big reason why, you
know, I was able to, you know, sign to
the 90man roster after mini camp.
>> I think I think all of my kids may might
be like three to six months older than
yours. So, I mean, but roughly all in
the same same age group, same, you know,
same grade. And uh I mean, I don't think
we right away talked about it at all cuz
we're both trying to figure it out.
>> We both
don't know what to do. You know,
probably feeling bad for our poor wives,
trying to trying to navigate life and
we're just playing football. Um but no,
it's been awesome to see um his family
grow um right alongside mine. And um you
know, I just watching your kids just
love being around you guys playing
sports. Um you know, Asher Asher is the
man, man. Uh all all of them are great
and just how athletic they are and how
much you guys care um about them and
more so just about, you know, who they
become. Uh I can see that. I I've seen
that in you and uh you know it's it's
something that I've looked up to even
though my kids are a little bit older.
Um you guys you guys are older than us
and um you know there's there's there's
a lot of wisdom in the things in in in
the way that you guys do things.
>> Yeah. I think I it's always nice to have
someone in the locker room that is
relatable, right?
>> Same situation. Um you know very similar
timing of getting married and and kind
of navigating the NFL with first of all
just starting with being married in the
NFL and then started adding kids. You
have one kid. Okay. How was that? And
and you know we could go back and forth
like hey did you sleep last night? Nope.
And just having that someone to relate
to and then you know in the offseasons
even we spent a lot of time in the
offseasons together and same things. And
then now our kids you know that got the
next phase of like starting to play
sports. So asking out Skyler you know
what she's doing gymnastics and the time
commitment and just kind of you know
that that's so huge just to have friends
and and people that are in the same
situation um that can really relate to
what you're going through. So, um, that
was obviously great through the years
and just seeing how you guys handle
things with, you know, making sure that
you're you're committed here in the
building, but also committed to your
family, how that time management um you
can always learn from other people,
which which I've I've always kind of um
admired that about you guys and and you
of how you really make time for your
family um which is important.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I think the best thing about
all that is and you know I've seen this
in you more than more than anyone is you
don't do it to get that recognition or
to receive an award or to be highlighted
like and you you feel that right when
you're when you're at these events like
you're not there thinking like oh man I
got to go do these events so I can get
these awards or or that I can get this
recognition. Um you're just serving.
You're just out there to to give back um
to a community that means a lot to both
of us, right? And I think it means a
little bit extra to us uh because we've
spent our whole lives in Minnesota and
so the people in Minnesota just mean a
little bit more to us and and it just
it's it's more gratifying when you're in
the moment than you are when you're
receiving the recognition or or an
award. So um you know I I learned from a
lot of great people in front of me. um
the Chad Greenways, the Kyle Rudolphs,
um you know, so many people, Brian
Robersonson, like there's so many people
in in front of me that really showed me
how to give back, how to get in the
community, how to how to really be a
leader off the field. Um and so that's
always was my thing was was I I needed
to show the next generation like what it
means to have that time management, when
to do it, how to do it. Um, and then
supporting your teammates, you know,
just all the events that we've had, you
you and your wife have showed up. Um,
your family showed up and uh, and that
means a lot to us. And then obviously
with the softball game and you guys kind
of took that over and and really ran
with it. So, um, those things are huge,
too, because I remember I remember how
much that meant to the other guys when
we would show up and then and then vice
versa for us when we were doing these
events. like it means a lot when guys
show up and and actually want to be a
part of it and give back even though
it's not for them necessarily. So, um
that was pretty cool.
>> Yeah. I mean, I I think I think I think
you guys laid laid the foundation, you
know, like like you said, you know,
showing showing the younger generation
and like, you know, growing up in the
Boys and Girls Clubs and all these
things. I say these things many times
like I've always wanted to give back.
I've always had a had had a heart to,
you know, try and spread love as in any
way I can. And sometimes you just don't
know how to do that, where to do that.
Um, especially with the platform that we
have and like you and Caitlyn showed us
the way, you know, showed us showed us
how how how we can impact different
communities and in so many different
ways and not even just with money, but
just showing up, being there. Uh, I mean
that that is something that my wife and
I, Steph, have have seen through you
guys so much and allowing us to, you
know, be a part of the softball game.
Bring bring awareness to your
foundation, our our scholarship fund.
Uh, you know, we just can't thank you
guys enough for showing us the way. Um,
and showing us how to use our platform
in the right way, not to get the the
awards, which are, you know, they're
great. I'm thankful. I'm humbled. Um,
but at the end of the day, it's just
about serving people, loving people,
seeing people, meeting people where
they're at. And um I think I think you
and Caitlin do a phenomenal job of that.
>> Yeah. Well, I'd say that Minnesota loves
their own as I'm sure you felt uh and
and I remember even being a kid and if
there was like Joe Mau like Minnesota
guy like you just have this extra like
you know you love those Minnesota guys
that go on and do big things even when
they're on other teams but obviously
when they're in Minnesota it's it's
really special. So, you feel that from
the fan base. Um, and still do, you
know, every every time we come back, you
know, uh, even when we were in Carolina,
uh, you come back and it's like,
"Welcome home. Good to have you back."
You know, there's just so much love and
support. And, uh, again, that's what
makes you want to give back even more
because there's been such support and
just a backing from, um, from this
organization and and just the people
that that follow the Vikings and and uh,
you've I've felt it my my whole career.
>> Yeah. No, I mean it's it's been it's
been unbelievable my my entire career
and obviously over these last handful of
years being on a team for so long. Um
you know more people notice you and
recognize you and I I I truly do take it
as a blessing. Like if if if I can make
someone's day by take taking a picture
with them, I'm going to I'm going to do
it for as long as I can. Um you know and
and it's it's it's because of that love
and support that motans give each other.
Um that's that's truly what that's truly
what it's about, man. And uh yeah, man.
I I love being I love being from
Minnesota. I love I love the fan base. I
mean, it's I know I know soon down the
road it'll wash away, but for now I'm
just going to take it all in and and
just continue to, you know, try to
brighten somebody's day, you know.
>> Showing blitz. Rams bring it. Keen gets
rid of it. Thelen makes the move. Adam
Thelen
off to the races. Touchdown.
>> Yes. I believe it was against the Rams.
I think maybe 28. No, 2017, I believe,
against the Rams where you took that
hitch route for like 60 yards, right?
>> Yeah.
Head head was cocked back. You know, you
know, everybody always talks about, oh,
Adam's not that athletic. He's not that
fast. Um, and he takes a five yard route
for 60 and doesn't get caught. And, uh,
you know, that was kind of just that.
and looking at everybody like, "Yeah,
yeah, I I I got it." I run I ran a 44.
Um and you know, ever since that day, um
I've always had his back. When everybody
when whenever anybody talks about, "Oh,
he's not that fast. He's just savvy.
He's just smart." It's like, dude, Adam
ran a 44. He's jumped like a 40inch
vertical. Like, he's he's he's he's an
athlete, you know?
>> Just find zones, man. Find zones.
Uh for me, for me, I mean, there's
there's so many um plays that people
don't notice with CJ, just on special
teams, you know, blocking and and
everyone sees the running back get come
free and and have a big run. But we're
just getting there. And and the best
part is when you're on the field or or
when you're on the sideline, you hear it
and then all a sudden you see someone
pop out and and have a long run. Uh but
but for me now obviously looking back at
it I think it was you know the last play
that you scored the touchdown
>> behind JJ CJ Ham in front of Ty
Chandler. HAND OFF CJ HAM PLOWS UP THE
MIDDLE TO THE END ZONE. TOUCHDOWN
VIKINGS. WELL DONE, CJ HAM. AND THE
Minnesota
>> watching that, seeing you score and
just, you know, I wasn't in the
building, but I, you know, from the TV,
you could feel it. And then the
sidelines, you know, just that showed
me. Obviously, I already knew this, but
like it showed everyone else how much
you're loved by everyone in that locker
room.
>> It they were blocking like it was their
brother. As you watch CJ Ham come to the
sideline, everybody is just excited for
CJ Ham and what he's meant to this
program
>> and how much people care about you and
want you to have success. So, for me,
that sticks out. I just thought that was
a a really cool moment that I'm sure
you'll remember for forever. And we got
to have kind of both sides of things
because we got to be in the locker room
together in the intense season, six
months of like you're in the grind, like
all that. And then like all the things
we talked about with our families and
the conversations we'd have way outside
of football.
>> Um but then we got the offseason where
it was like more relaxed. We weren't
stressed. You know, we weren't worried
about wins and losses or performance.
Like we were just in there grinding
together and laughing, having fun, kind
of the same group that we've had for a
while. Um you know, those are the things
I'm going to miss for sure. Um, but I
can't I can't think of any like crazy
funny stories. But I mean, I think I
think it's cool, too. We had we had some
emotional times together, too. Like
shared things with each other that, you
know, were really tough times like that
that helped us get through some tough
times. Um and and so those are the
things that like that you're you're
going to miss, you know, because you
don't have that where there's 50ome guys
in a locker room that you get to hang
out with every day that are again a lot
of them some of them are very relatable
what you're going through in your in
your life. So, uh I definitely will
always cherish those moments inside the
building and and in the offseasons. Mhm.
No, I was definitely going to speak to
more so just how much time we spent
together in the offseasons. I mean,
probably what the last seven years or so
every offseason um from this time
through the summer just training
together every day at 8:00 a.m. in the
morning. Um and again, can't think about
I mean I can't necessarily think about
all the specific things we talked about.
I just I just keep thinking about all
the laughs, though. Like I'm talking
about we're in a two twohour workout and
we're like laughing the entire time. Um
just because of just little things here
and there or someone says something
funny or you know Adam looks at the
weights and just says you know what I'm
good
>> pick up my kids pick up my kids. So um
yeah those those are the times that uh
I'm probably going to miss the most. Um
and I know we're we're still here
together. We're about to start play
playing basketball together. probably
getting some probably getting some
workouts in together as well. So, um
there will be some more times in the
future as well.
>> Even though CJ's younger than me, his
faith was a lot stronger than mine. And
so, so CJ CJ really was a mentor, one of
my greatest mentors in my faith walk and
forever grateful for that. Um, and those
are those conversations I'm talking
about that had nothing to do with
football that we've had some amazing
conversations, just life stuff that
happened in life that we could kind of
talk about and just help each other out
through or maybe sometimes it was just
listening. Yep.
>> And uh, and so yeah, I mean, I wouldn't
be where I am in my faith walk if it
wasn't for you.
>> Um, and just just your consistency with
it even through some of the tough times
you were going through and just your
honesty, right? just because you're a
Christian, just because you believe
doesn't mean you're perfect. And so just
your honesty, um it really helped me
because I I feel like at for a long time
I felt like as a Christian you had to be
perfect. And if you weren't, you just
don't talk about it.
>> And so when you were so honest and open
and and and you really were living the
word, um it made me understand what a
real Christian is supposed to look like.
And that's not perfect. And that's just
telling people that and being honest
because a lot of people might be going
through the same thing. But if you don't
share it, uh they they never would know.
>> I appreciate that, man. Definitely don't
deserve that at all. So I I I definitely
appreciate it, man. And um it's, you
know, to answer your question, it's it's
it's amazing to, you know, have a
brother in Christ on the team. You know,
when you when you find out when you find
out somebody shares the same faith faith
as you, you gravitate gravitate towards
that person. um you kind of you kind of
you kind of feel that trust and um you
know that was that that that was
automatic man. I mean just from our our
background growing you know somewhat
growing up growing up together in this
in in this football football world um
and then just realizing that like you
are another man who fears God um you
know leads his family and you know
through the tough times you know I saw
how steadfast you were. I saw how I saw
how much you you you stayed grounded in
what you believed in and even though
things weren't perfect, you're like, you
know, I'm still gonna try to be better.
Uh, you know, I'm I'm still I'm still
going to give it my all. Um, so just I
just commend you on just how steadfast
you have been your whole career. Um, and
just continuing to uh, you know, lay lay
it all out there and how unapologetic
you you you have always been. You know,
you you love to talk. you know, I'm I'm
not so much I'm not so much the uh the
out outgoing talker unless you know,
unless I unless I know you very well,
but uh you know, I think it was this
this year in in uh in Europe, uh how you
just were sitting at a table and you
just asked somebody like, "Man, how you
know, how how's your faith walk?" You
know, having no idea what this person
believed in. Um you just said you felt a
nudge to ask someone. And like that
right there was encourage encouragement
to me is that like hey you can be bold.
You can ask questions and just don't be
afraid to talk about your talk about
your faith even if you don't have the
answers. Um you know we need to we need
to let people know what we believe in
and hear about what other people believe
in as well. Um and because we can we can
still relate. We can still come together
even if even if we don't believe the
same things. And just that courage that
you've shown um over the years, how
unapologetic you've been um and how you
go about sharing your faith um is pretty
cool to see.
>> There's his wife Stephanie, his family.
I wonder what the future has in store
for CJ Ham. If you think that they don't
know about it, that he's thinking about
pondering potentially the end.
>> It it had been brought up quite a few
times,
>> maybe the last couple years.
Uh but yeah, I mean I think again that's
like the best part with the locker room
is you get to kind of have these
conversations
>> and sometimes it's like you know it's
doesn't mean anything. It's just
venting, you know, and and sometimes
there's there's truth to it and there
and it's real. Um and so we've kind of
walked that path together over the last
couple years. Um and so yeah, I think it
was pretty clear that we knew that this
was probably approaching.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And you know, even even
through those conversations, even you
know, while while we were training in
the offseason together, it's like it
makes it makes those times even a little
bit more special, you know, um you know,
when we get to do these things together,
when we get to go out to go out to
practice. Um you know, knowing that
we've done it together for so long and
um you know, now, you know, now now the
days are numbered, you know, and um
truly truly a blessing, bro. Like being
your teammate, you being my brother for
so long, bro. Like there's not enough
words that I can say that truly express
like the relationship and how I feel
about you and what you've meant to me in
my career. U like I know it's not over
obviously like we still going to be
friends but uh you know
>> excited for basketball.
>> Exactly. Exactly. I I I just wish I had
the vocabulary to say to to say the
words that I like I I truly want to say,
man. So from the bottom of my heart,
man, I love you. Appreciate you, bro.
>> Appreciate you. Yeah.